25 Yosemite Dr., New Orleans, LA 70131 × (504) 496-8662 × alexrudenko12@gmail.com

#### EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

Mr. Rudenko is a highly experienced and certified as Project Manager Professional (PMP) with previous expertise in management of the design and construction of the \$2.4B Capital Improvement Program. The work involved managing consultants and contractors providing design, project and program management, utility coordination, testing and inspection, and construction services for the City's Capital Infrastructure Improvement Program. Managed City of New Orleans public works infrastructure FEMA-funded projects, including roadways, drainage and public utilities through all phases of project delivery from initial planning, design, construction, and project closeout. Provided city management with accurate and ongoing status reports, recommended solutions for project issue resolution, coordinated design quality control and assurance, and managed contract, budget and claims.

For FEMA Regions I, III and IV, provided technical support under the FEMA's Public Assistance Program to develop Project Work Sheets (PWs), Scope of Work (SOWs) and Cost Estimates (CEFs) for damaged facility restoration like: Roads and Bridges; Buildings and Equipment; Water Control Facilities; Utilities; Parks, Recreations and other. Successful and timely completed over 300 projects to date. Produce and validate Scope and Cost for all Categories of Work (Cat. A-G); Standard/Specialized/Completed Lane Projects; Facilities eligible for replacement under 50 Percent Rule. Manage EHP, Hazard Mitigation and Inspection concerns. Excellent understanding of FEMA processes. Demonstrated knowledge and understanding of civil engineering and design, project management, engineering hydraulics, structural steel and concrete design, materials and testing. Knowledge of engineering software, such as, SACS, RISA, AutoCad, AutoCad Civil 3D. Certified Safety Inspector of In-Service Bridges (National Highway Institute).

#### EDUCATION

B.S. Civil Engineering, University of New Orleans, 2011-2013
2000 Lakeshore Drive, New Orleans, LA 70148.
Project Manager Professional Certified, Project Management Institute, 2022.
Product Manager Certified, Product School, 2022.

#### REPRESENTATIVE EXPERIENCE

#### Senior Project Manager / Executive Lead – RNM Consultants, Inc

Provide subject matter expertise for the various types of public works infrastructure and capital improvements projects (FEMA, Bond, State, Hazard Mitigation, Green Infrastructure, etc.) including roadways, drainage and public utilities through all phases of project delivery from initial planning and design to construction and project closeout. Manage cross — functional teams and responsible for team collaboration. Serve as a team Facilitator to empower a group to be more effective and focused, often with an emphasis on open communication and trust. Remove roadblocks and assisted to move project forward. Reach out to external stakeholders, identify potential projects and promote the company products. Performer Risk Management, develop frameworks to minimize risk and identified new risk.

25 Yosemite Dr., New Orleans, LA 70131 × (504) 496-8662 × <u>alexrudenko12@gmail.com</u>

Prepare plans for variety of construction projects using computer applications such as AutoCad Civil 3D, InRoads, MicroStation and HYDR2009), for technical design computations to determine plan quantities for earthwork, pipe sizes and lengths, drainage inlets spacing and locations, guardrails, base courses, asphaltic concrete, Portland cement concrete pavement and striping.

# <u>Civil Engineer / CRC East Cost Specialist – Fluor Corporation (Federal Emergency Management Agency CTR).</u>

Successful and timely completed over 300 projects to date under the FEMA's Public Assistance Program. Perform Disaster Related work for all Disasters in FEMA Region I, III, IV (Covers 20 States: Connecticut, Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, Rhode Island, Vermont, State of Delaware, District of Columbia, State of Maryland, Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, Commonwealth of Virginia, State of West Virginia, Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Kentucky, Mississippi, North, Carolina, South Carolina, Tennessee). Produce and validate Scope and Cost (CEF) for:

• All Categories of Work (Cat. A-G), Standard/Specialized/Completed Lane Projects; Facilities eligible for replacement under 50 Percent Rule.

Excellent understanding of FEMA processes. Utilize RS Means to develop Cost Estimates. Proficient in the use of Excel and Grants Manager for validating/estimating projects. Ensure all project information is consistent and adequately supported by source documentation.

#### <u>Senior Civil/Structural Engineer – Keystone Engineering Inc.</u>

Provide structural and foundation design of medium to large size engineering projects with minimum or without supervision for industrial (refineries, plants, terminals, pipe racks) or offshore structures (production platforms, wind farms). Define and review scope of work, prepare engineering estimate at both proposal and design level and schedule for civil/structural engineering and design portion of work in a project. Prepare accurate and complete designs and calculations as required to meet project requirements, applicable codes and industry standards. Coordinate and direct drafting and design workflow to produce construction drawings.

Perform Engineering Design for Listed below Clients:

- Rain Carbon Inc. Chalmette, LA
- Chevron Pipeline Chalmette, LA
- Enterprise Products Cushing, OK
- Marathon Oil Atascosa County, TX
- ExxonMobil MP 133 B, MP 133 CB
- Arena ST51, ST 52, ST37
- Orsted Block Island, RI

# <u>Senior Civil Engineer – Fluor Corporation (Federal Emergency Management Agency CTR).</u>

Serve as Assistant to Task Force Leader (PD-TFL), DR4332TX - Hurricane Harvey. Perform projects Peer Review and training of team members. Provide technical expertise to develop Damage Descriptions and Dimensions (DDDs), Statements of Work (SOWs) and Cost

25 Yosemite Dr., New Orleans, LA 70131 × (504) 496-8662 × <u>alexrudenko12@gmail.com</u>

Estimates (CEFs) for the restoration of the damaged facilities assessed for use by FEMA in developing project worksheets for Building Assessment Team (BAT). Perform assignments under the Public Assistance Alternative Procedures (PAAP) Permanent work requiring an expert review.

Serve a function of CRC Specialized Lane Technical Specialist to produce and validate Scope and Cost for:

- Substantially damaged facilities, per floodplain management requirements
- Facilities eligible for replacement under the 50 Percent Rule, including relocation of essential facilities
- Substantial Damaged Facilities Building Elevation
- Substantial Damaged Facilities Floodproofing
- Critical infrastructure projects such as a public utility (WTP, WWTP, lift station, electrical substation, and the like), dam replacement, bridge, beach, sea wall, levee, etc., which has severe damage and cannot be restored to pre-disaster condition

#### Project Manager - Capital Improvement Program, DPW City of New Orleans.

Performs professional work in managing the design and construction of the \$2.4B Capital Improvement Program. The work involves managing consultants and contractors providing design, project and program management, utility coordination, testing and inspection, and construction services for the City's capital infrastructure improvement program. Responsible for the various types of public works infrastructure capital improvements projects (FEMA and Bond), including roadways, drainage and public utilities through all phases of project delivery from initial planning, design, construction, and project closeout. Manage 10-20 projects simultaneously and established strong, productive, collaborative relationships. Periodically prepare and review and/or updated project execution plans. Work closely with Sewerage and Water Board of New Orleans and other City Departments to define project scopes of work, resource requirements, budgets, schedules, and deliverables. Oversee consultant architecture/engineering firms for design and construction administration. Provide city management with accurate and on-going status reports, recommended solutions for project issue resolution, coordinated design quality control and assurance, and managed contract, budget and claims. Communicate progress effectively with team members, senior management and the funding agencies, FEMA and GOHSEP.

#### Structural Engineer - Keystone Engineering Inc.

Design of the sub-structure and foundation for use in offshore, including multi-pile platform Designs, deck design, barge analysis, loadout, tiedowns and ballasting arrangements, foundation design, piling and support structure design, dynamic, fatigue and seismic analysis, drainage design, installation analysis.

#### Engineer I - Hatch Mott MacDonald.

Professional engineering design and surveying services for FEMA-eligible street repairs. Developing preliminary design plans, final plans, cost estimate, specifications, and bid documents for use in the reconstruction of damaged roadways, curbs, utilities, and driveways.

25 Yosemite Dr., New Orleans, LA 70131 × (504) 496-8662 × alexrudenko12@gmail.com

#### SKILLS

- Highly trained, motivated, and detail-oriented Project Manager with an undergraduate Civil Engineering degree.
- Demonstrate knowledge and understanding of civil engineering and design, project management, engineering hydraulics, structural steel and concrete design, materials, and testing.
- Knowledge of engineering software, such as, RISA, SACS, AutoCad, AutoCad Civil 3D, RSMeans.
- Certified Safety Inspector of In-Service Bridges (National Highway Institute).
- Possesses excellent verbal and written communication skills, and has advanced practical experience in MS Word, Excel, P6 and Power Point presentations.

#### EMPLOYMENT

4/2020 – Present (Remote Work)

Senior Project Manager / Executive Lead, RNM Consultants, Inc.

1/2020 – Present (Remote Work)

Civil Engineer / CRC Cost Specialist, Fluor Corporation, Inc.

7/2019 - 1/2020

Senior Civil/Structural Engineer, Keystone Engineering Inc

4/2019 - 6/2019

Senior Civil Engineer, Fluor (Federal Emergency Management Agency CTR).

6/2015 - 4/2019

Project Manager, New Orleans Department of Public Works.

5/2014 - 6/2015

Structural Engineer, Keystone Engineering Inc., Offshore Renewables Department.

6/2013 - 5/2014

Engineer I, Hatch Mott MacDonald

10/2002 - 5/2007

Assistant Construction Manager (Internship) – Bytservice, Mylokaiv State, Ukraine.

#### CODES AND STANDARDS

International Organization for Standardization (ISO),

American Institute of Steel Construction (AISC),

Manual of Steel Construction (ASD),

Det Norske Veritas (DNV),

American Petroleum Institute (API),

National Association of Corrosion Engineers (NACE).

Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA)

DPW General Specification for Street Paving 2015

25 Yosemite Dr., New Orleans, LA 70131 × (504) 496-8662 × <u>alexrudenko12@gmail.com</u>

# MEMBERSHIP

American Public Works Association American Society of Civil Engineers

### REFERENCES

Available upon request